So how concerned should investors be?
Joining me now is Matt Miskin. He's
co-chief investment strategist at
Manulife John Hancock Investments. It's
great to have you here. I mean, this is
a really great place to start. Yesterday
on the show we talked about Palantir
before they reported earnings. We didn't
know what they were going to be. The
analyst here said he had great
expectations but still had a hold on the
stock and a lower price target because
of the valuation. Do you feel like we're
in dangerous territory with Palantir and
some of these higher flying tech stocks
because so much of the market Matt has
really ridden on the coattails of these
trades.
Yeah, Courtney Palantir is likely in the
epicenter here of this kind of AI
euphoria.
For us, we don't like companies that are
trading at 100 plus PE ratios. But the
way that we're looking at valuations
today is relative to the growth. So we
use what's called a PEG ratio. So it's
the PE divided by the growth rate. And
while Palantir's growth rate is pretty
compelling, you're coming off a very low
base. And we're looking for high quality
companies with low PEG ratios. So things
like the return on equity, good balance
sheets. Because to us, moving up in
quality makes a lot of sense when
there's valuation risk. We want to make
sure these these businesses are built to
last for a long time. We think about
investing in a longer term nature.
Earnings growth is coming in great.
Technology is a big part of that. We're
just trying to decipher through this
market, find the best companies with
higher ROE and low PEG ratios. Okay, so
that is that's interesting. The PEG
ratio as opposed to this PE ratio ratio
that we're so focused on. Can you give
us some examples now that we understand
your theory? What are you looking at?
Yeah, I mean, within the technology
sector, the earnings growth in aggregate
is 20%. So while the the PE ratio is
elevated when you normalize the verse of
20% earnings growth run rate, it's
pretty reasonable, frankly.
Communication services is actually
pretty compelling. Healthcare and even
industrials when you look into 2026.
Industrial earnings have actually been
really compelling in this quarter.
So overall, the the hardest part about
this market has been keeping up with
these great growth companies because of
the valuations and the concentration
risk. In our view, having that lens
where you're normalizing valuation to
the growth rate can help you keep up
with this market but not necessarily
outperform. We're actually okay keeping
up with this market and not necessarily
outperforming. We're trying to draft it.
So being a bit behind is okay in this in
a more heavily valued market. We're just
holding on to those companies that have
the best growth rate earnings potential.
That is that is an interesting theory. I
like that you gave us some examples
there, too. And I'd love to talk about,
obviously, the
economic situation that we're dealing
with right now. It's a little bit hard,
obviously, to tease one out from the
other when we're talking about companies
versus the economy. But I because I
think we have to sort of put them
together. When we heard what the Fed had
to say, or Jerome Powell at least, and
sort of the discussion that we've now
understood might have happened before
they came up to their decision. It seems
like there is some fear that the economy
is slowing down, but companies are doing
fairly well and and you're talking about
the overall 2025 earnings growth
estimate being revised up. Also the 2026
earnings estimate being revised higher.
So is is the economy not having a drag
down effect?
So at the end of the day, we need the US
consumer to spend. And the US consumer
needs jobs. And so at the end of the
day, AI can't spend money. I mean, I
know that's the biggest
reason why the feedback loop of this AI
narrative just doesn't work. Because AI
can make businesses more productive. One
of our mega themes is doing more with
less, having businesses more productive.
How do you invest in that? But at the
same time, we need consumers to have
jobs. And the jobs market is weakening.
We think the Fed made a policy mistake
last week coming out more hawkish.
In a bit of a conspiracy theory, it may
be that they're trying to be hawkish now
because they believe that there's going
to be a different Fed
in terms of, you know, how they're going
to attack their goals into 2026. That
hawkish tilt going into the end of the
year with a government shutdown may
produce more of a negative impact to the
economy than they're looking for. So
we're just going to have to see. Actions
speak louder than words for the Fed. So
they did cut. They are stopping QT,
which are definitely dovish and good
things for the economy. But being a bit
hawkish at the press conference from
Powell to us is not what you want to
signal to the market in a pretty pretty
fragile economy.